savingmorethanme.com 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy » Winter and Sparrow

(updated May 4, 2018)

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Statement of Privacy applies to winterandsparrow.com and governs data collection and usage. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to Winter and Sparrow include winterandsparrow.com. The Winter and Sparrow website is a Home and Lifestyle site. By using the Winter and Sparrow website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of your Personal Information**

In order to better provide you with products and services offered on our Site, Winter and Sparrow may collect personally identifiable information such as:

  * First and Last Name
  * E-mail Address

Winter and Sparrow may also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your:

  * Age Range
  * Gender
  * Geographic Location

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Winter and Sparrow’s public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. We do not collect any personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us. However, you may be required to provide certain personal information to us when you elect to use certain products or services available on the Site. These may include: (a) registering for an account on our Site; (b) entering a sweepstakes or contest sponsored by us or one of our partners; (c) signing up for special offers from selected third parties; (d) sending us an email message; (e) submitting your credit card or other payment information when ordering and purchasing products and services on our Site. To wit, we will use your information for, but not limited to, communicating with you in relation to services and/or products you have requested from us. We also may gather additional personal or non-personal information in the future.

**Use of your Personal Information**

Winter and Sparrow collects and uses your personal information to operate its website(s) and deliver the services you have requested. Winter and Sparrow may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Winter and Sparrow and its affiliates.

**Sharing Information with Third Parties**

Winter and Sparrow does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Winter and Sparrow may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. Winter and Sparrow may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Winter and Sparrow, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Winter and Sparrow may disclose your personal information, without notice, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Winter and Sparrow or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Winter and Sparrow; and/or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Winter and Sparrow, or the public.

**Tracking User Behavior**

Winter and Sparrow may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within Winter and Sparrow, in order to determine what Winter and Sparrow services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Winter and Sparrow to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

**Automatically Collected Information**

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by Winter and Sparrow. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain the quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Winter and Sparrow website.

**Use of Cookies**

The Winter and Sparrow website may use “cookies” to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Winter and Sparrow pages, or register with Winter and Sparrow site or services, a cookie helps Winter and Sparrow to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on.

When you return to the same Winter and Sparrow website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Winter and Sparrow features that you customized. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Winter and Sparrow services or websites you visit.

You can learn more about cookies at [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Advertising**

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is [Mediavine.com](https://www.mediavine.com/). These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

You can opt out of network-based advertising at the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/).

**Links**

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

Winter and Sparrows is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

**Security of your Personal Information**

Winter and Sparrow secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Winter and Sparrow uses the following methods for this purpose:

  * Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol

When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol. We strive to take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or alteration of your personal information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations inherent to the Internet which are beyond our control; and (b) security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this Site cannot be guaranteed.

**Children Under Thirteen**

Winter and Sparrow does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website.

**E-mail Communications**

From time to time, Winter and Sparrow may contact you via email for the purpose of providing announcements, promotional offers, alerts, confirmations, surveys, and/or other general communication. In order to improve our Services, we may receive a notification when you open an email from Winter and Sparrow or click on a link therein. If you would like to stop receiving marketing or promotional communications via email from Winter and Sparrow, you may opt-out of such communications by clicking on the UNSUBSCRIBE button.

**External Data Storage Sites**

We may store your data on servers provided by third party hosting vendors with whom we have contracted.

**Changes to this Statement**

Winter and Sparrow reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account, by placing a prominent notice on our site, and/or by updating any privacy information on this page. Your continued use of the Site and/or Services available through this Site after such modifications will constitute your: (a) acknowledgment of the modified Privacy Policy; and (b) agreement to abide and be bound by that Policy.

**Contact Information**

Winter and Sparrow welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. We can be reached at pr(at)winterandsparrow(dot)com.
